so in a poll on facebook we asked
what tim tams people preferred we put up
three flavors and everyone chose the
chewy caramel ones
so
had a look online
found the tim tam slam i'm sure you all
know about that but if not we'll talk
about it later but for now let's check
this out
i want
a packet of tim tams that never runs out
you have two wishes left then we'll have
two more of those
on it's tim tam what more could you want
[Music]
right so now we're gonna take one of
these chewy caramels
it's not a penguin
and let's try this tim tam slam
it just explodes in your mouth it's
great the chewy caramel one i think
that's a good choice obviously i've
never had these other two so
maybe we'll try that after
now that more loaded up with chewy
caramel tim tam
i had these years ago but they're really
difficult to get over in the uk i mean i
think
these ones cost about eight pounds a
pack to get them here so
you know
it's not really an everyday purchase
but everyone voted for the chewy caramel
version which is these
caramel gooey camo through the middle
chocolate cream
biscuit chocolate coated great
i just didn't want to stop there i
actually wanted to make some of the
other flavors so
today i'm gonna make three different ice
creams lots of split screen lots of you
know fancy kind of video editing that
we're gonna try
but i'm really looking forward to these
coffee ones
i mean let's be fair
the salted caramel ones
they're not going to be disgusting so
it's going to be a complicated one stick
around
we'll show you how everything's done
so we're going to start with the chewy
caramel tim tam base where you're going
to add your milk and most of your sugar
into that give it a nice little stir so
the sugar dissolves properly then add in
your milk powder this actually isn't a
particularly good one it doesn't
dissolve very easily but hopefully yours
is a bit better than this then i'm using
powdered dolce de leche here but if you
haven't got that or you can't get it
just use normal wet delta delhi and add
that to your mix get it nicely combined
and here i'm adding the last of the
sugars with the stabilizer in it get
that up to the temperature required for
your chosen stabilizer when it's ready
remove it from the pan put it in a
container and here we're going to add in
our cream which will bring the
temperature down nice and quickly before
we look at moving on
to our next ice cream base
this one is the dimboola coffee so we're
going to take our beans and get them
nicely chopped up add them into our milk
on the hob
warm it up gently and let it sit there
for about half an hour so that flavor
really infuses into the milk at that
stage you can take it off and strain it
through a cheesecloth or a really fine
sieve get all those little bits out make
sure you get all the last little bit of
yummy coffee milk out there once you've
got all of that done and strained add
that coffee milk back to the pan now
here we're gonna add in our corn syrup
you can add golden syrup which is what i
use here
and all of our sugars this includes the
dark brown sugar that adds a lovely bit
of caramelization and really enhances
that coffee flavor
give it a nice stir and again in goes
the skimmed milk powder get it nicely
combined and make sure there's no more
lumps left
at that point again take it off the heat
add in your cream again to bring that
temperature down nice and quickly and
put that one in the fridge
and finally we're going to move on to
the murray river salted caramel base now
again in with the milk into your pan
here we're going to add our sugars
our single egg yolk
give it a nice stir
and this is the point that we're going
gonna add our previously made
caramel now that comes next in the video
so hold firm we'll show you how to make
that
add it to your base and get it nicely
dissolved
it might take a minute or two depending
on how hot or cold your caramel is
once it's stirred and well combined
add in your milk powder
give that a really nice stir make sure
it's all lovely and smooth and there's
no lumps
now here is where i've added just a
touch too much salt for most people it's
fine for me i've adjusted the recipe
below so you get a really nice punch of
salt but not overpoweringly so
when that's ready take it off the heat
like the others
put it into a container
add your cream to bring that temperature
down and put it in the fridge
now we're going to get working on these
add-ins now to start with we're going to
go with the tim tam fudge so take some
of your chewy caramel tin tams and chop
them up nice and small and just put them
in a little container because we're
going to use them in a second
in a pan add your milk and your cream
make sure you get all that lovely
delicious cream out of there and then
add in your sugar and give that a nice
little stir to dissipate that sugar and
start that dissolving then add in your
corn syrup you can add golden syrup
which is what i use here
corn syrup isn't available in the uk
get that stirred together and then add
in your cocoa powder you need to bloom
the cocoa powder bring it up to a nice
high temperature but with this fudge and
all fudges really for ice cream you need
to get it boiling get it really nice and
hot and that will change the sugar
structure so that it's nice and soft and
gooey in your ice cream and doesn't go
all i see
once that's ready turn the heat off
let it calm down for a minute or two and
then add in your chopped tim tams give
it a nice stir and put it in a container
ready to use later
now the milk chocolate fudge is quite
similar to the tim tam fudge you're
adding your milk and your sugar but here
we're going to add a little bit of
coconut oil and again in with our corn
syrup or golden syrup depending on
whereabouts in the world you are get
that stirred together add in your cocoa
powder let it get nice and hot bring it
to a good rolling boil turn the heat off
and then add in your chopped milk
chocolate
give it a nice stir make sure all that
chocolate is completely melted and take
it off the heat and store that in a
container
finally onto the caramel so add your
sugar to a pan and swirl it around don't
stir this at all keep swirling on a
gentle heat until all that sugar melts
down until you've got this lovely
caramel color here at this stage turn
heat off and add in your butter
it might bubble up a little bit while
you do this so be careful get it nicely
combined and then pop in your cream i've
used cold cream here which is why it's
reacted quite as violently as it has but
you can warm that cream up if you need
to
get it nicely mixed together and then
put that in a container we'll use that
again later
[Music]
that was a lot of ice cream and a lot of
add-ins and it's taken me
bloody ages to make i mean let's be fair
uh we've got a freezer full of ice cream
it's never a bad thing
let's get somebody scooped up we'll do
them individually and see how these
things turned out
anyone that's watched this channel for
more than probably two weeks will know
that i do all these
videos on sunday morning this is no
different but this is special because i
get to eat biscuits and ice cream
never a bad thing
so
murray river salted
caramel biscuits
now they're the same shape as the
penguins tim tams are made and
were developed in competition with the
uk penguin
the whole history thing i'll put some of
it up here or here
and i mean penguins are shockingly bad
biscuits how they even can compare to
these penguins are horrid compared to
these things so
let's try one
really nice
a little bit chewy caramel inside
not as much salt as i thought but
still really good really soft
let's see how the ice cream
goes whether it works
definitely put salt in that
probably a little bit too much but
i'm happy with it i'm just not sure
other people would want that much salt
i'll adjust the recipe below
to probably a more acceptable amount of
salt for this sort of camel
caramel flavor is really nice
it's subtle doesn't overpower some
caramels are really strong
and you lose track of what it is and it
just becomes this hit of sugar
this is really nice the caramel
obviously goes quite hard in the ice
cream but as it melts in your mouth you
get that little bit of salt come through
in the actual physical caramel itself
really nice
let's move on to the next one shall we
the coffee one dambulla coffee
again more biscuits
such a shame
smell the coffee
they're really nice
coffee cream
looks like a darker biscuit
yeah that's really good let's um
let's compare the ice cream
that is surprisingly close the coffee
flavor is surprisingly close
that's that is that has actually taken
me back a little bit but
i mean this is a great coffee ice cream
it's just a little bit
chewy but just the right amount good
strong coffee flavor and that chocolate
fudge that goes through there
nice little break up and that kind of
imitates the chocolate going around the
biscuit itself
that's really nice really really nice
let's move on to
the last one which is the one that
everybody voted for the chewy caramel
tim tam and ice cream combo
right let's try this one
chocolate tim tam fudge
chewy caramel ice cream caramel swell
[Music]
chewy caramel tim tams
chewy caramel ice cream
over stabilized on purpose
to create that chewy texture
the tim tam chocolate fudge
breaks it up little nice additions of
those crunchy bits in there that's a
really nice texture change
and the caramel ribbon throughout
also really nice
you get it all stuck in your teeth so
you taste it for ages
three ice creams these are bloody good
ice creams tim tam you should take these
and make them into something just
remember that i gave you the idea
but i hope you've enjoyed this unique
approach to tim tams
i hope you try some of these ice creams
if you like this approach to videos let
us know i'm not probably going to do
them quite this complicated and big for
a while but
we are going to do some series videos in
so if you're interested in what they'll
be like
make sure you like and subscribe thanks
very much for watching and we'll see you
next time